halfords.ie 2018-05-25

# Help & Advice | Customer Services | Policies & Regulations

  * Terms and Conditions
  * Terms of Use
  * Privacy Policy
  * Cookie Policy
  * Chemical Regulations
  * Terms for free in-store WiFi

## Terms and Conditions

### 1\. Introduction

Halfords Group PLC ("Halfords") is the UK's leading retailer of car parts, car enhancement, camping and touring equipment and bicycles, and the UK's largest independent operator in garage servicing and auto repair.

As an essential part of our business, we collect and manage customer data. In doing so, we observe UK data protection legislation, and are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and rights.

In order that you are reliably informed about how we operate, we have developed this Privacy Statement. Together with any additional Privacy Notices which you may see as you navigate around this website, this Privacy Statement describes the ways in which we collect, manage, process, store and share information about you as a result of you visiting this site.

This Privacy Statement also provides you with information about how you can have control over our use of your data.

Please note that we will be updating this Privacy Statement on a regular basis in order to keep you fully up-to-date with our approach to data protection and privacy. If you have any comments or queries regarding our use of your data, or you wish to unsubscribe from receiving marketing communications from us, please contact our Data Protection Officer ("DPO") by email at: [ dataprotectionofficer@halfords.co.uk](mailto:%20dataprotectionofficer@halfords.co.uk) or by post at: **Data Protection Officer, Icknield Street Drive, Washford West, Redditch, B98 0DE.**

### 2\. What Information Do We Collect About You

The information that we collect about you may include your name, home address, date of birth, e-mail address, telephone number, as well as relevant financial and credit card information. This is referred to as your "personal data". We collect this data in a number of different ways. For example, you may provide this data directly when filling in forms on this website, or when corresponding with us by telephone, e-mail or letter.

Equally, when you visit this website and even if you do not register with us, we may collect technical information about you such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address which connects your computer or mobile device to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, the country and telephone code where your computer is located, and information about your visit including products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors and length of visits to certain pages.

Only in very rare instances will we need to collect any sensitive information about you (known as "special categories of data") which includes, for example, details about your racial or ethnic origin, or data relating to your health. Should it ever be necessary for us to ask you for this type of data, we will provide you with separate details about how we will protect that information at that time.

### 3\. How Will We Use That Information?

Currently, we use your data for the following purposes:

  * **3.1** To assist in the processing of your order / to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us. For example, this could include packing and delivering orders, forwarding order details, order fulfilment, the processing of credit/debit card transactions, fraud prevention, registering warranties and the provision of corresponding customer services

In certain circumstances, it may be necessary for us to provide your information to external companies with which we contract to assist us in providing these critical services to you. We assure you that these companies are not permitted to use your information for any other purpose. For further information about these companies, please see section 5 below.

  * **3.2** Where you have given us your specific consent, we will use your data to provide you with marketing services. This allows us to tell you about new products or services that may be of interest to you. Again, we do use a number of external companies to help us provide such marketing services. However, these companies are prohibited from sharing your data with any other company. This means that by consenting to receive marketing from us, you will not receive marketing communications from anyone else.

  * **3.3** To ensure that the information contained within this website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer or mobile device. This information allows us to update and improve the contents of our site, and ensure the smooth operation of internal processes, such as troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes, and to keep our website as safe and secure as possible. For further information, please refer to our Cookies Policy, which can be found [here.](http://www.halfords.com/advice/customer-services/policies-regulations?topCategoryId=292503#tab_cookiepolicy)

  * **3.4** To understand what sections of the website you are visiting, so that we can subsequently contact you regarding particular products and services which may also be of interest. This facility is enabled by cookies, described in our Cookies Policy which can be found [here.](http://www.halfords.com/advice/customer-services/policies-regulations?topCategoryId=292503#tab_cookiepolicy) We do this as we think it is important to understand your shopping and browsing habits so that we can keep improving our service for you. 

  * **3.5** To share with other companies within our Group, where we believe there may be additional benefit for you. However, before we send you any marketing from these other Group companies, we will always first seek your explicit consent. A full list of the companies within our Group is available at [www.halfordscompany.com](http://www.halfordscompany.com/)

If you change your mind at any stage about receiving marketing from us, or if you do not want us to process your personal data for one or more of the reasons set out above, please contact our DPO as described in section 1 above.

### 4\. How Long Will We Keep Your Data?

Unless you ask us to do so, we will never keep your data for longer than is necessary for us to complete the activity for which your data was collected in the first place. However, sometimes there is a legitimate and/or legal reason that means we need to retain your data. In the coming months, we will add further detail to this Privacy Statement, setting out further information about our practices. 

### 5\. With Whom Do We Share Your Personal Data?

We work with a number of external suppliers who support our business. This includes organisations which are critical to fulfilling customer orders as detailed in section 3.1 above, as well as those that help us with marketing, as detailed in section 3.2 above. In the coming months, this Statement will be updated to give further detail about the categories of suppliers that we use, specifically where these organisations are based outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). We will also provide details about the security arrangements which are in place in order to protect customers? data. 

Notwithstanding the above, we assure you that we will only exchange your data with another organisation where i) we have your express permission to do so; or ii) it is necessary in order to honour a contract between you and Halfords; or (iii) we have a legal obligation to share the information; or (iv) it is in the public interest; or (v) it is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or (vi) it is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or another person.

We will never sell your personal data to any external organisation.

### 6\. How Can You Access The Personal Data We Hold? 

You have the right to ask us, in writing, for a copy of all the personal data we hold about you. This is known as a "Subject Access Request". Except in exceptional circumstances (which we would discuss and agree with you in advance), you can obtain this information at no cost. 

We will send you a copy of the information within 30 days of your request.

To make a Subject Access Request, please write to our DPO at the postal address shown in section 1 above. 

### 7\. Updating or Amending Your Personal Data 

If, at any time, you want to update or amend your personal data or consent preferences, please contact our DPO as described in section 1 above. Any requested and legitimate changes will take effect within 28 days of receipt of your request.

### 8\. Data Privacy and Security

We maintain a comprehensive data management work programme, which includes processes for ensuring that data protection is a key consideration of all new and existing IT systems that hold customers? personal data. Where any concerns, risks or issues are identified, we conduct relevant impact assessments in order to determine any actions that are necessary to ensure optimum privacy.

We also maintain an active information security work programme which seeks to protect the availability, confidentiality and integrity of all physical and information assets. Specifically, this programme helps us to:

  * protect against potential breaches of confidentiality;
  * ensure all IT facilities are protected against damage, loss or misuse; and
  * increase awareness and understanding across our business of the requirements of information security, and the responsibility of colleagues to protect the confidentiality and integrity of the information that they handle.

We recognise that the security of data and transactions on this website is of primary importance. We therefore ensure that all connections to secure parts of the website (such as your personal account and the checkout section) are encrypted and authenticated using strong protocols, key exchanges and ciphers.

### 9\. Location Tracking Via Our Website

This website only uses geo-location tracking, which shows us where you are in the UK, for specific situations. These include:.

  * **click and collect:** on the product pages, you can check the availability of any selected item in your local store;
  * **store locator:** you can search for your local store using your current location In both situations, your permission will be sought before geo-tracking is used, and then, it is only used to personalise your experience.

### 10\. Card Payment Security

We are proud to have been awarded the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS), which recognises the robust processes that we apply when handling card transactions from the major card schemes. This independent certification gives our customers assurance that our transactional systems protect your data with appropriate levels of security.

### 11\. Disclaimers

Every effort is made to ensure that the information provided on this website, and in this Privacy Statement, is accurate and up-to-date, but no legal responsibility is accepted for any errors or omissions contained herein. 

We cannot accept liability for the use made by you of the information on this website or in this Privacy Statement, neither do we warrant that the supply of the information will be uninterrupted. All material accessed or downloaded from this website is obtained at your own risk. It is your responsibility to use appropriate anti-virus software. 

This Privacy Statement applies solely to the data collected by us, and therefore does not also apply to data collected by third party websites and services that are not under our control. Furthermore, we cannot be held responsible for the Privacy Statements on third party websites, and we advise users to read these carefully before registering any personal data. 

### 12\. Accessibility Statement 

We are committed to providing a website in which content is accessible to everyone. We therefore update our website regularly in order to make it as adaptable as possible. 

For example, website users can control the text size of each page within their internet browser. On a PC, holding the ?Ctrl? key while pressing the ?+? (plus) key will increase text size, and holding the ?Ctrl? key while pressing the "-" (minus) key will decrease the text size. 

However, should you require a copy of this Privacy Statement in a different form, please contact our DPO as described in section 1 above. We cannot guarantee that we can fulfil all requests, but we will endeavour to help you as much as practical.

### 13\. General

The Data Controller of this website is Halfords Group PLC, Icknield Street Drive, Washford West, Redditch, Worcestershire B98 0DE. 

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Statement are welcomed, and should be sent to our DPO.

Back to top

## Terms of Use

These terms set out how you may use our websites and our App. Please read these terms of use carefully, together with our Privacy Policy before you start to use any of our sites or our App. By using any of our sites or App you confirm that you accept these terms and that you agree to comply with them. If you do not agree to these terms of use, you must not use any of our sites.

### Access

We do not guarantee that any of our sites or our App, or any content on them, will always be available or be uninterrupted. We may suspend, withdraw, discontinue or change all or any part of our sites without notice. We will not be liable to you if for any reason one of our sites is unavailable at any time or for any period. We may limit the availability of our sites or any service or product described on any one of our sites to any person or geographic area at any time.

### No Reliance on Information

We have taken every care in the preparation of the content of our sites and our App. To the extent permitted by applicable law, we disclaim all warranties, express or implied, as to the accuracy of the information contained in any of the materials on any of our sites and our App. Due to the changing nature of the information contained on our sites and our App we shall have no liability whatsoever for any damages or losses arising directly or indirectly as a result of any of the information accessible via the sites and the App not being accurate, complete or up to date.

### Viruses

We do not guarantee that our sites or our App will be secure or free from bugs or viruses. Due to the nature and inherent risks of communications and the transfer of data over the internet, we shall have no liability whatsoever for any damages or losses resulting from viruses, worms, Trojan horses or other malicious code or the corruption or loss of data or any damage to software or hardware. You should use your own virus protection software.

You must not misuse any of our sites or our App by knowingly introducing viruses, Trojans, worms, logic bombs or other material which is malicious or technologically harmful. You must not attempt to gain unauthorised access to our sites our App, the server on which our sites or our App are stored or any server, computer or database connected to our sites or our App. You must not attack our sites or our App via a denial-of-service attack or a distributed denial-of service attack. By breaching this provision, you would commit a criminal offence under the Computer Misuse Act 1990 and we reserve the right to report any such breach to the relevant authorities.

### Registration

You warrant that the personal information which you are required to provide when you register as a user of one of our sites or our App is true, accurate, current and complete in all respects. You agree not to impersonate any other person or entity or to use a false name or a name that you are not authorised to use. You will notify us immediately of any changes to the personal information you have provided us with.

### Intellectual Property Rights

All copyright, trademarks and all other intellectual property rights in all material or content supplied as part of our sites or our App shall remain at all times vested in us or our licensors. You are permitted to use this material only as expressly authorised by us or our licensors.

You may download extracts of any page(s) from our sites or our App for your personal use or in accordance with any contractual relationship we have with you. However, you must not modify the paper or digital copies of any materials you have printed off or downloaded in any way, and you must not use any illustrations, photographs, video or audio sequences or any graphics separately from any accompanying text identifying the authors of content on our sites or our App.

### Social Media

These terms also govern any submissions you make on any third party website related to us or page such as any of our Facebook pages, Twitter, Pinterest, YouTube or social networking sites. All comments, images, videos and any other type of material posted on any third party social networking site do not necessarily reflect our opinions or ideas nor those of our employees and we are not responsible for any such content. In any event, all material posted on any third party social networking site must comply with these terms and the third party social networking sites' terms of use, as applicable.

Whenever you make use of a feature that allows you to upload content to our sites or our App, or to make contact with other users of our sites, you must comply with the acceptable standards set out in these terms.

### Acceptable Standards

Any and all material which you contribute to any of our sites or our App (" **contributions** "), and to any interactive services associated with them must comply with the following standards. Contributions must not:

  * Contain any material which is defamatory of any person or be threatening, abuse or invade another's privacy; or be likely to harass, upset, embarrass, alarm or annoy any other person.
  * Contain any material which is obscene, offensive, hateful or inflammatory including any sexually explicit material or promoting violence. 
  * Promote discrimination based on race, sex, religion, nationality, disability, sexual orientation or age.
  * Infringe any copyright, database right or trade mark of any other person.
  * Be made in breach of any legal duty owed to a third party, such as a contractual duty or a duty of confidence.
  * Promote any illegal activity.

You agree that you will only use our sites or our App for lawful purposes and will not:

  * Use them in any way that breaches any applicable local, national or international law or regulation.
  * Use them in any way that is unlawful or fraudulent, or has any unlawful or fraudulent purpose or effect.
  * Transmit, or procure the sending of, any unsolicited or unauthorised advertising or promotional material or any other form of similar solicitation (spam).
  * Knowingly transmit any data, send or upload any material that contains viruses, Trojan horses, worms, time-bombs, keystroke loggers, spyware, adware or any other harmful programs or similar computer code designed to adversely affect the operation of any computer software or hardware.
  * Reproduce, duplicate, copy or re-sell any part of our sites in contravention of the provisions these terms of use.

We will determine, in our discretion, whether there has been a breach of the above acceptable use requirements through your use of any of our sites or our App. When a breach of our requirements has occurred, we may take such action as we deem appropriate including immediate, temporary or permanent withdrawal of your right to use our site or our App and/or legal action.

### Interactive Services

We will do our best to assess any possible risks for users from third parties when they use any interactive service provided on our sites or our App, and we will decide in each case whether it is appropriate to use moderation of the relevant service (including what kind of moderation to use) in the light of those risks. However, we are under no obligation to oversee, monitor or moderate any interactive service we provide on our sites or our App, and we expressly exclude our liability for any loss or damage arising from the use of any interactive service by a user in contravention of the above requirements, whether the service is moderated or not.

### Third Party Links

Certain links on our sites and our App will lead to websites which are not under our control. When you activate any of these you will leave our site/App and we will have no control over and will accept no responsibility or liability for the material on any website which is not under our control. We assume no responsibility for the content of websites linked on our site and our App. Such links should not be interpreted as endorsement by us of those linked websites. We will not be liable for any loss or damage that may arise from your use of them.

### Applicable Law

These terms of use are governed by English law and subject to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of England and Wales. Nothing in these terms of use excludes or limits our liability for death or personal injury arising from our negligence, or our fraud or fraudulent misrepresentation, or any other liability that cannot be excluded or limited by English law.

Thank you for visiting our site.

Back to top

## Chemical Regulations

Halfords supplies many chemical-based products online, via our catalogue and in-store. All retailers selling chemical products are obliged to comply with European directives by providing key health and safety information for this type of product. Several key European Directives/Regulations exist governing the supply of chemical products with regard to labelling, packaging and marketing and these regulations also require health and safety documentation to be made readily available.

The Regulations themselves are designed to protect both the environment and human health, and as a responsible supplier Halfords naturally takes its obligations very seriously and ensures it complies and enforces these regulations.

[Halfords Health and Safety information](http://www.my-sds.co.uk/default.asp?accountid=guest&languagecode=44&companyid=halfords) for chemical products provides access to the latest up-to-date label information, Safety Data Sheets and Detergent Ingredient Data sheets.

To access further information, follow the link above, then select ’Name’ for the search criteria in the left-hand drop-down box, and in the box underneath, enter either the full name of your product if know, e.g. Halfords 5W30 VW Fully Synthetic Oil, or a generic name, e.g. oil, click ’Search’, and all the products we have information on will be displayed in the box to the right. Then simply click on the rectangular symbol to display the safety data sheet, or the diamond symbol to display the chemical supply symbol. 

Should you have any queries regarding this or any other safety issues please contact our customer services department

Back to top

## Terms for free in-store WiFi

### Halfords WiFi

These are Halfords Limited's ( **Halfords** , **we** or **us** ) terms for the provision of wireless and broadband communication services which allow you to access the internet via our WiFi networks ( **our service** ) when you are either located within or close to any of the participating Halfords stores. You should understand that by using our service, you agree to be bound by these terms.

Please read these terms carefully. By choosing "Register" on your mobile phone you will choose to use our service. If you do not accept these terms, you will not be permitted to use our service.

### **Provision of the Service**

When using our service, you agree at all times to comply with our Terms of Use and our  Privacy Policy.

It is your responsibility to ensure that your mobile device is compatible with our service and is switched on. The availability and performance of our service is subject to all memory, storage and any other limitations in your mobile device. Our service is only available to your mobile device when it is within the operating range of participating Halfords stores. Our service is subject to non-availability, including non-availability due to emergencies, collocation failures, transmission and equipment limitations, or maintenance and repair, and may be interrupted, refused, limited or curtailed.

Halfords are not responsible for data, messages, or pages that you may lose or that become misdirected because of interruptions or performance issues with our service or wireless communications networks generally. Halfords may impose usage, or service limits, suspend service, or block certain kinds of usage in Halfords sole discretion, to protect other users of our service. Network speed is no indication of the speed at which your mobile device or our service sends or receives data. Actual network speed will vary based on configuration, compression and network congestion.

Halfords does not warrant or guarantee the performance of the internet or that the transmission of information over the internet will be secure or that the internet will be accessible at all times. You agree to use these services entirely at your own risk.

### Use of the Service

You may access our service in accordance with these terms for your own personal use. You agree not to resell any aspect of our service, whether for profit or otherwise, or to authorise any other third party to use our service. You agree not to use our service for any illegal, fraudulent, obscene, unlawful, harassing, or abusive purpose, including the sending of any unsolicited commercial text or email messages in such a way as to create damage or risk to Halfords' business, reputation, employees, subscribers, customers, facilities, or to the public generally. You agree not to intentionally transmit any computer viruses or do anything that is likely to interfere with the provision of our service.

Halfords are not responsible for any sites that you access whilst using our service, or any activities that you carry out on the internet (including any items which are downloaded from the internet). Halfords does not guarantee that products or services or any sites accessible via our service are error or virus free. All such activities are carried out at your own risk and it is your responsibility to ensure that you have the right to carry them out. Third party sites will have their own terms and conditions, terms of use and privacy policies which will apply if you access third party sites. Please check these terms and policies before you use any third party sites or carry out any activities in connection with them.

We have the right to suspend or terminate our service immediately in the event that you breach any of the provisions of these terms, our Terms of Use, or our Privacy Policy including without limitation:

  * if you use any equipment which is defective or illegal;
  * if you cause any technical or other problems to our service;
  * if, in our opinion, you are involved in fraudulent or unauthorised use of our service;
  * if you resell access to our service; or
  * if you use our service in contravention of the Terms of Use.

### Privacy and Data Protection

Privacy cannot be guaranteed and Halfords will not be liable to you for any lack of privacy that you experience while using our service.

We shall process all information about you which is provided in relation to our service in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

While we agree to take all necessary technical and organisational steps to ensure the security of our service, we are not responsible for the accidental loss or destruction of any personal data you transmit using our service and we exclude all liability of any kind in relation to the content or security of personal data that you send or receive through our service.

You agree and acknowledge that we may be required by law to provide assistance to law enforcement, governmental agencies and other authorities. Accordingly, you agree:

  * that we may implement and maintain an interception capability suitable to meet these requirements where we are obliged by law to ensure or procure that such a capability is implemented and maintained;
  * that we may implement and maintain a data retention capability for our service to meet requirements where we are obliged by law to ensure or procure that data is retained; and
  * we may at times co-operate with law enforcement authorities and rights-holders in the investigation of any suspected or alleged illegal activity by you. If we are required to do so by law, this may include but is not limited to, disclosure of your contact information to law enforcement authorities or rights-holders.

We will use your personal data for the purposes set out in our Privacy Policy. You acknowledge and accept that Halfords may use your personal data for marketing purposes to contact you (by post, email or SMS) about products and services which we feel may be of interest to you. If at any time you no longer wish to receive information from us, please email us at [customer.services@halfords.co.uk](mailto:customer.services@halfords.co.uk)

### Our Liability

Halfords' maximum aggregate liability to you for losses or damages suffered in respect of all claims arising in connection with these terms shall not exceed £500.

To the extent permitted by law, we, other members of our group of companies hereby expressly exclude:

  * all conditions, warranties and other terms which might otherwise be implied by statute, common law or the law of equity; and
  * any liability for any direct, indirect or consequential loss or damage incurred by you in connection with our service, including: loss of income or revenue; loss of business; loss of profits or contracts; loss of anticipated savings; loss of data; loss of goodwill and whether caused by tort (including negligence), breach of contract or otherwise, even if foreseeable, provided that this condition shall not prevent claims for loss of or damage to your tangible property or any other claims for direct financial loss that are not excluded by any of the categories set out above.

This does not affect our liability for death or personal injury arising from our negligence, nor our liability for fraudulent misrepresentation or misrepresentation as to a fundamental matter, nor any other liability which cannot be excluded or limited under applicable law.

### General

We will not be liable or responsible for any failure to perform, or delay in performance of, any of our obligations under these terms that is caused by events outside our reasonable control ( **Force Majeure Event** ).

These terms and any dispute or claim arising out of or in connection with them or their subject matter or formation (including non-contractual disputes or claims) shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the law of England and Wales and the courts of England and Wales shall have exclusive jurisdiction to settle any dispute or claim that arises out of or in connection with these terms.

Back to top
